<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE roms SYSTEM "rominfos.dtd">
<roms>
<info>
	<set>2020bb</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK/Pallas</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Baseball</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc>Another NeoGeo Baseball game following on from the success of the acclaimed BaseBall Stars Professional. This game takes a futuristic approach to the sport, in that over-the-top japanese kind of way. The graphics are very colourful and fairly well drawn, and unlike some of the other earlier neogeo games, the animation is mostly quite good. While this game tries to be futuristic with its flashy graphics, at heart its not that different from Baseball Stars Professional. I am not a great follower of baseball myself, as we dont see much of it in the UK, but from what I can tell the game remains fairly accurate to the sport. As far as sound goes there are the usual whacks, cheers and some computerised responses from the umpire. As for the home version (set 2), the differences are hardly noticeable. Overall if you like Baseball then youll probably enjoy this. </desc>
	<rating>12</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>3countb</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Wrestling</genre>
	<year>1993</year>
	<size>106</size>
	<desc>While there is a huge number of fighting games for the NeoGeo, as far as I know this is the only Wrestling game. The graphics are suitably bold and large and reflect the typical atmosphere of a wrestling match. The Zoom effect which was first used in Art of Fighting is also put to good use. Sound effects are what you would expect from a wrestling match, each wrestler has their own range of grunts groans and screams, and there is a voice over commentary before every match. There are 10 wrestlers to choose from each with a suitably over-the-top range of moves and outfits in the traditional american wrestling style and the game plays convincingly, with grapples, holds, throws, punches and kicks as well as special attacks ranging from suplexes to breathing fire. Overall this is a good solid playable game and should especially appeal to wrestling fans, particularly as their choice is somewhat limited.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>alpham2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Vertical Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>47</size>
	<desc>This game features an unusual menu based power-up which can make the controls seem a little cumbersome at first, its all too easy to get your ship destroyed whilst trying to use the menus, but with practice the game does play fairly well. It does however look a little dated when compared with some of the later games.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>androdun</set>
	<manufacturer>Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Horizontal Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>32</size>
	<desc> This shooter has a very cartoon-like feel to it which is slightly unusual for this kind of game, in some places it looks almost *cute*. Its not an over-the-top blast frenzy like some other neo shooters but seems to play more like r-type, one interesting feature is the weapons, your ship comes pre equipped with a range of selectable weapons so you dont have to rely on a feeble weapon until a powerup comes along. You also continue from where you left off when your ships are destroyed, rather than having to repeat half the level again and again when you reach a difficult part</desc>
	<rating>12</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>aodk</set>
	<manufacturer>ADK/SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>178</size>
	<desc>One of the More unusual NeoGeo fighting games, its a cross between a scrolling fighter and a one on one fighter as you can walk in-to and out-of the backgrounds, so it has a slightly wierd feel, but it plays well once you get used to it.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>aof</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>102</size>
	<desc>This was one of the first fighting games to appear on the NeoGeo it features enormous character sprites and a zoom feature which gives a close up view of the action when the characters are near to each other. Personally I really like this game, but thats probably because I remember playing it years ago when it first appeared, there was a great atmosphere to the single player story mode, but by todays standards it is somewhat limited, for example the single player mode only has two playable characters, and there is no true combo system, but the game is still very playable it is more of a slower paced tactical beat-em up than some of the newer fighting games such as the King of Fighters series. The sound features the usual beat em up style sound effects along with a bit of speech for some of the special moves. There are plenty of beat em ups for the NeoGeo and this is by no means the best of them, but it does have some unique features which make it more than worth playing.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>aof2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>178</size>
	<desc>There were a number of criticisms of the original Art of Fighting, Mainly the lack of characters in the single player game and the speed of the game. With the sequel SNK gave the players what they asked for- 12 Playable Characters, each with a story of their own in the single player game and overall faster gameplay. In terms of Graphics and sound the style remains quite similar to the original but with some general improvements to the quality, also the game is still more tactic based than combination based, I cant seem to find a proper combo system such as in the king of fighters games. Overall It is a good game with many improvements over the original, but I cant help but feel that some of the atmosphere of the first game has been lost in this sequel.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>aof3</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>298</size>
	<desc>This is the third and (I think) final game in the Art of Fighting series. The game has a differnent look and feel about it to its predecessors. Probably the first thing people will notice is that the graphical style has changed and the animation has been massively improved, every character has been motion captured from a real person for ultra-smoooooth movements, it is probably the best animation in any NeoGeo game ever, even better than the newer King of Fighters games. The game also continues the story theme of the previous Art of fighting games but again improves upon it, its now almost like watching a film. The sound effects and music remain consistent with the previous games but have been jazzed up for the third incarnation. Fans of the first two games will immediately notice that Aof3 plays rather differently than before, the zoom-in feature is not so pronounced and the new combo system allows you to *juggle* your opponent with hits in the air, the controls can feel strange at first but you soon get used to it and find that it is a very playable game.</desc>
	<rating>17</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>bakatono</set>
	<manufacturer>Monolith</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Mahjong/RPG</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>48</size>
	<desc>This game appears to be a hybrid of japanese mahjong and a role playing game, unfortunately almost all the ingame text is in japanese, thus making it somewhat difficult to play.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>bangbead</set>
	<manufacturer>Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Airhockey</genre>
	<year>2000</year>
	<size>170</size>
	<desc>This game appears to be very similar to both Windjammers and Battle Flipshot, continuing the same airhockey theme- hit all of your opponents markers with the ball to win whilst guarding your own.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>bjourney</set>
	<manufacturer>Alpha Denshi</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Platform</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>50</size>
	<desc>This is one of those cute and colourful platform games, which you either love or hate, I suppose its aimed at kids, but then how many kids could afford almost $700 for the console and game? It plays ok, but is nothing special, the makers have tried to introduce some RPG-like elements into it such as shops where you can buy items to aid your quest, but it is fairly simplistic.</desc>
	<rating>9</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>blazstar</set>
	<manufacturer>Yumekobo</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Horizontal Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1998</year>
	<size>346</size>
	<desc>Blazing Star is one of the later NeoGeo games, it is an Anime Style shoot-em up and the sequel to the game Pulstar. One of the first things which strikes you about this game is the quality, there is enormous attention to detail and superb graphics, even the intro sequence is like watching a film, Ive no idea how they managed to fit it all into one cartrige. Most of the graphics have been rendered from 3D models rather than being drawn and as such the game has a very 3D look about it even though it is two dimensional. The sound is excellent too the effects and music make a refreshing change to the usual stuff, they have a distinct Robotech japanese feel to them. As for the gameplay the game does not disappoint there are 5 ships to choose from all with different abilities and weapons and there is a massive range of enemies. Also this game doesnt suffer from the dreaded restart points which in my opinion spoiled Pulstar, it becomes very tiresome having to keep repeating a difficult part again and again if you keep getting destroyed, but in this game you can just carry on from where you left off.
Overall I reckon this is the best scrolling 2D shoot-em up of its type on the NeoGeo, An excellent game.</desc>
	<rating>18</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>breakers</set>
	<manufacturer>Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>210</size>
	<desc>Many people have compared this one-on-one fighting game with Capcoms Street Fighter Alpha, mainly because of its multi-level super move bars, but this game is by no means a copy of SF Alpha. Breakers is a fast paced beat-em up with some spectacular special moves and effects, the super moves in this game are particularly worth seeing as tagging one on the end of a combo can easily give you a 20 hit string of attacks. The graphics are bold and bright and there are some nice backgrounds but it is the flare and glow effects resulting from a hit or a victory which really make the game look flashy. Add some suitably beefy sound effects and an evil booming voice for the final boss and youve got a very enjoyable game.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>breakrev</set>
	<manufacturer>Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1998</year>
	<size>242</size>
	<desc>Breakers Revenge is not exactly a sequel but more of an update of the game Breakers, in the same way Champion Edition was to Street Fighter 2. This version adds a new character, the ninja Saizo and some new graphics on the intro and player select screens. other than that there is not a whole lot of difference between this and the original. but it is worth playing just to experiment with the new character.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>bstars</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Baseball</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>50</size>
	<desc>One of the very first NeoGeo games, and its still just as playable as it was when it was released, It helps if youre a fan of baseball though.</desc>
	<rating>12</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>bstars2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Baseball</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>68</size>
	<desc>The sequel to the acclaimed Baseball Stars Professional, it features bigger and better graphics and plays just as well as the original.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>burningf</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Fighter</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>54</size>
	<desc>When the NeoGeo first appeared in the arcades its main rival was Capcoms CPS1 System whos games included Street Fighter 2 and Final Fight, this game is (in my opinion) SNKs attempt to create Final Fight for the NeoGeo, as at that time there were virtually no other scrolling beat-em ups. Graphically the two games are very similar, The characters Ryu and Duke are remarkably similar to Guy and Cody from Final Fight. Unfortunately while SNK was able to create a similar looking game Burning Fight feels sloppy when compared to Final Fight, you dont feel that your punches and kicks are making contact and the (limited) combo system which added a little variety to the button bashing in Final Fight is nowhere to be found, so you find yourself pressing buttons completely at random. The game is fairly playable for a short while, but eventually it just becomes too repetitive. The sound is nothing special either just your usual whacks and groans. Overall I suppose Its not a bad first attempt at what was then a new genre, but now it just feels a bit dull. Its just as well SNK have made up for it with some of their more recent games.</desc>
	<rating>9</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>ctomaday</set>
	<manufacturer>Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Vertically scrolling shooter</genre>
	<year>1999</year>
	<size>106</size>
	<desc>This is a bit of an odd one, a superhero tomato created in a lab accident flies around punching various fruit shaped baddies. The game seems similar to Pop and Twinbee on the Snes, and is quite playable, but you will get crippled fingers as theres so much button bashing involved.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>crsword</set>
	<manufacturer>Alpha Denshi</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>First Person Combat</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>50</size>
	<desc>This is one type of game which seems to be unique to the NeoGeo, its a First person sword fighting game, and there seems to be few others like it besides Crossed Swords 2 for the NeoGeoCD and Super Spy. It is quite original but it can get a bit repetitive as the range of moves is a quite limited.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>cyberlip</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Platform/Scrolling shooter</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>50</size>
	<desc>This is a kind of cartoonish version of the arcade shooter Midnight Resistance, its not a bad platform shooter considering it was an early NeoGeo game, but it looks a bit dated these days.</desc>
	<rating>10</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>diggerma</set>
	<manufacturer>Game Room</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	<year>2000</year>
	<size>44</size>
	<desc>Well, This is an odd one, It appears to be a Prototype game for the NeoGeo which was never actually released as a finished product. It has no NeoGeo boot screen and does not have any of the usual graphical style which is familiar in other games, in fact it seems more like a game from the early 16-bit era. It is a fairly entertaining for a short time but it does get repetitive and irritating after a while.</desc>
	<rating>6</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>doubledr</set>
	<manufacturer>Technos</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>178</size>
	<desc> Many people remember the Double Dragon games from a few years ago, a series of scrolling beat-em ups featuring the brothers Jimmy and Billy. They tried very hard to be popular and original but always seemed to fall at the final hurdle - Gameplay, their lack of moves and repetitive button bashing always seemed to end up being tedious, but little did many of us know that lurking away on the NeoGeo there was a different kind of Double Dragon game which was actually quite good. NeoGeo Double Dragon is a one-on-one beat-em up with a good selection of characters and moves and most importantly great gameplay. Some of the backgrounds are also quite original such as the fight on the wings of a plane as it flies down a canyon and the exploding walls and buildings.
Overall this is a much better game than any previous double dragon efforts. if youre a fan of one-on-one fighting games youre sure to like this.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>eightman</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK/Pallas</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Fighter</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc>Another attempt at a scrolling fighter for the NeoGeo, unfortunately eightman is not much of an improvement over Burning Fight, its just a case of run along and keep hitting punch until the enemies fall over, and it still doesnt feel like youre actually hitting anything. Its fun for a while but gets repetitive.</desc>
	<rating>8</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>fatfury1</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>55</size>
	<desc>One of the NeoGeos first attempts to lure gamers away from Capcoms Street Fighter series, its quite playable but is rather limited by todays standards, as there are only three playable characters in single player and not many special moves or combos.</desc>
	<rating>12</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>fatfury2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>106</size>
	<desc>Although many people hoped it would be, Street Fighter 2 was never ported over to the NeoGeo, but SNK fought back against its popularity with their own fighting games such as this, there are 8 playable characters just like in SF2 and the game plays in a similar way too. its just a question of which one you prefer.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>fatfursp</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1993</year>
	<size>150</size>
	<desc>This game is SNKs answer to Capcoms Super Street Fighter 2. it has all the features of Fatal Fury 2 with some extra characters, moves and stages.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>fatfury3</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>266</size>
	<desc>This game feels much more solid and playable than its predecessors, there are some great new characters, and you can see that distinctive style of art which SNK adopted starting to appear.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>fbfrenzy</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>American Football</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>48</size>
	<desc>I think this is the only American Football game on the NeoGeo, I dont really have a vast knowledge of how the actual game works, but from what I can tell this is a fun to play and fairly accurate re-creation of it.</desc>
	<rating>12</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>fightfev</set>
	<manufacturer>Viccom</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>American Football</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>98</size>
	<desc>Considering when this game was released (the same time as the first King of Fighters game) the graphics are rather poor, in places they look worse than the original Fatal Fury, despite the fact that this game is four years newer. It seems to play OK but its certainly nothing special, and not a patch on Kof 94.</desc>
	<rating>10</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>flipshot</set>
	<manufacturer>Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Skill/AirHockey</genre>
	<year>1998</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc>This game is simple and fun to play, with some nice graphics. You must deflect the ball away from your side of the arena and knock down your opponents markers. It seems similar to WindJammers, but is less irritating.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>galaxyfg</set>
	<manufacturer>SunSoft</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>169</size>
	<desc>This is a very good quality fighting game with some nice Anime style characters and special effects such as rain and reflections when you fight in water. But it does seem to be very difficult, even in the early fights.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>ganryu</set>
	<manufacturer>Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Platform/Fighter</genre>
	<year>1999</year>
	<size>178</size>
	<desc>I havent had the opportunity to play this game yet, but it appears to be scrolling platform/fighter in the style of Ninja Warriors. Obviously I cant comment on exactly how it plays, but from the shots Ive seen it doesnt look particulary revolutionary.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>garou</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1999</year>
	<size>688</size>
	<desc>What can I say? Its another neogeo beat-em up, a kind of *next generation* for the Fatal Fury series (I think Terry is the only original character to appear). It has probably some of the best character animation in any of the games, a wide selection of new characters and moves and another new twist on the super-move formula. Theres nothing outstandingly new here, but if you like this kind of game (and most neogeo fans do) then youll be more than happy with it.</desc>
	<rating>17</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>goalx3</set>
	<manufacturer>Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Football/Soccer</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>110</size>
	<desc>This is a solid playable football game, It has the usual fast-paced 2D arcade football feel to it, but the graphics are a little basic for a game released in 1995.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>gowcaizr</set>
	<manufacturer>Technos</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>186</size>
	<desc>This game has a similar feel to it to Galaxy Fight, but its not quite so stylish. There are some interesting characters though, such as Shaia who uses a robotic sphere to do all her fighting.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>gpilots</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Verticall Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>55</size>
	<desc>Another scrolling shooter, this time set in the past rather than the future, its nothing to shout about but it plays well, and has a similar feel to Capcoms 1942.</desc>
	<rating>12</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>gururin</set>
	<manufacturer>Face</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>40</size>
	<desc>One of the NeoGeos huge variety of bizarre puzzle games, in this one you have to line up different coloured people in the rotating box on the screen. its quite entertaining but a bit odd.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>irrmaze</set>
	<manufacturer>Face</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>106</size>
	<desc>Well, they sure named this game accurately, its based on one of those games where you have to guide a metal rod around a shaped ring without the two touching, or you set off a buzzer. Its the only NeoGeo game I know of which uses a trackball, and it really is irritating.</desc>
	<rating>10</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>janshin</set>
	<manufacturer>Aicom</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Mahjong/RPG</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>82</size>
	<desc>Another mahjong game, It looks as though its been combined with an RPG, but since I cant play it I cant review it.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>joyjoy</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>22</size>
	<desc>A variation on the Tetris theme, you have to complete the lines of blocks in order to release the trapped balloon before the timer runs out.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kabukikl</set>
	<manufacturer>Hudson</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>202</size>
	<desc>This One-On-One beat-em-up, it has a very stylised anime feel to it, its a kind of *cartoon-like* samurai shodown. Whilst not revolutionary it is a solid playable game.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>karnovr</set>
	<manufacturer>Data East</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>122</size>
	<desc>This Game is an update to Fighters History, and is also known by the name of Fighters History Dynamite. If I recall correctly Data East (the games manufacturers) had a battle of their own with Capcom, over similarities between this and Street Fighter 2, Although to be honest there are many other beat-em ups which are just as similar. The game itself plays in the typical beat em up style, you have fireballs, dragon punches etc. The game is nothing special but if you like one-on-one fighting games youll like this.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kizuna</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>242</size>
	<desc>Now this is a True Classic NeoGeo game, it is the sequel to Savage Reign (another game which added a new dimension to beatem ups) This games brilliance comes from its tag team feature and its control system, I believe this was the first game to introduce Tag Battles, which have since been seen in games such as Tekken and Dead or Alive.
Each player chooses 2 characters and you have the ability to switch between them any time you are standing in your Tag-Zone on the floor of the arena, your resting character also regains their health whilst in the background so you have to be tactical in your tagging. The Combo system is also excellent, it uses only 2 buttons for attack 1 punch and 1 kick but allows tou to add variations to your moves by using the direction pad, this lets you mix up your moves into combos really quickly as you dont have to switch attack buttons so often. Overall a really superb and original game which is just as playable now as it ever was.</desc>
	<rating>18</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kof94</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>196</size>
	<desc> The first game in the King of Fighters series, and another game to offer a new element to the 2D fighter genre, Kof94 adds another variation in the form of Team Battles you choose a fixed team of three fighters and choose a priority for each character (1st,2nd and 3rd) and battle against your opponents team, as each member of a team is defeated you move along to your second and then third characters. Whichever player defeats all three of their opponents characters first is the winner.
This game also tied some of SNKs fighting games together into one, bringing in characters from Art Of Fighting and Fatal Fury in addition to new characters created especially for KOF.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kof95</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>250</size>
	<desc>Kof95 is the second King of Fighters game, here the Team Battle action remains much the same as Kof94, but with the new addition of custom teams, you can now make a team of three from any of the characters in the game, adding a great deal more variety. This game also adds some extra characters and further improved graphics and animation.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kof96</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>362</size>
	<desc> Kof96 continues the Team Battle series with another range of game changes, some of which come from Real Bout Fatal Fury which was released just before this game. These include a modified chain combo system and variable POW special moves. There are also some character changes, six old characters have gone, having been replaced with nine new ones.
The changes do add improvements to the overall game but they dont make it significantly different, you really need to have played the previous games a lot to appreciate the changes.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kof97</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1997</year>
	<size>460</size>
	<desc>Kof97s enhancements include the options to choose between 95 and 96 gameplay styles as well as another range of character changes, again the modifications do improve the game but you need to have played the previous games to see the differences.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kof98</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1998</year>
	<size>683</size>
	<desc> At last Kof gets a much needed combo counter, its amazing how much difference this makes as you actually get to see your combo achievements displayed on screen, so you actually know when you managed to pull of that combo properly.
Other enhancements include more new characters, new moves and selectable character colours. </desc>
	<rating>17</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kof99</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1999</year>
	<size>673</size>
	<desc>Kof99 takes the best of the improvements from the series and merges them together into one of the best 2D fighters ever made, again there are numerous changes but they are too extensive to list, suffice to say that the gamer is now VERY complex, although is is still very playable even for beginners.</desc>
	<rating>18</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kof2000</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>2000</year>
	<size>688</size>
	<desc>Surprise surprise SNK have done it again, as you might expect, Kof2000, improves on its predecessors again, and by now you know what youre getting, so much polish you can see your face in it.</desc>
	<rating>18</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kof2001</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>2001</year>
	<size>892</size>
	<desc>Another year another KOF, I dont know how many more refinements they can put into this series, but theyll keep striving for the perfect 2D Fighter, and theyre getting pretty close...</desc>
	<rating>19</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kotm</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Fighter</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>55</size>
	<desc>King of the monsters is a quite original variation on the scrolling fighter theme, you choose from one of three monsters and battle a range of other beasts across the cityscape in true godzilla style. Certainly an interesting game, but ultimately it just comes down to frantic button bashing.</desc>
	<rating>11</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>kotm2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Fighter</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>74</size>
	<desc>This is much the same as the original game, but there are now extra moves and characters, plus you can battle multiple monsters at once.</desc>
	<rating>12</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>lastblad</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1997</year>
	<size>474</size>
	<desc>Another execellent SNK fighter, this one is set in ancient japan, much like samurai shodown, but with greater complexity. Great emphasis is placed on the use of your characters weapon and you can choose from two variations of each character Speed or Power which can have a range of effects on the way you play. The intro also deserves a special mention as it is very impressive.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>lastbld2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighting</genre>
	<year>1998</year>
	<size>554</size>
	<desc> Last Blade 2 adds more characters and features that its predecessor and again better graphics and animation.
The intro sequence is also even more impressive than the first game which is quite amazing.</desc>
	<rating>17</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>lbowling</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Bowling</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>26</size>
	<desc>A quick, simple and fun to play bowling game. This was one of the first neogeo games, and like Baseball Stars has stood the test of time fairly well.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>legendos</set>
	<manufacturer>Wave</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Fighter</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>50</size>
	<desc>Legend of Success Joe is another early neogeo game, and (I think) is supposed to tell he story of Joe and his rise to success as a boxer. The game takes the form of a scrolling beat em up, although it is ultimately rather dull. The controls are unresponsive and sluggish, (It feels like you are walking in tar) and the graphics are well... not great. If youre a big fan of scrolling fighters you may like this, but its not one of the best games on the NeoGeo.</desc>
	<rating>6</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>lresort</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Horizontally Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>45</size>
	<desc>A traditional arcade scrolling shooter, it offers the usual range of enemies and powerups and the additional feaure of a Pod powerup which you can control the aiming of, the pod shoots in the opposite direction of the last direction you pushed on the D-pad. This is in principal a neat idea, but when you have virtually zero space to move amidst the hordes of enemies and your weapons are firing in the wrong direction, And you combine this with the fact that one hit destroys your ship and you cant restart from the point where you left off, then youll be mighty irritated.</desc>
	<rating>11</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>magdrop2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>82</size>
	<desc>This is another variation on the Puzzle Bobble/Tetris theme, you control the little guy at the bottom of the screen, grabbing baloons of one colour down from the top then pushing them back up in a different place to join them with other similar coloured baloons, when a certain number of similar coloured baloons touch they explode. The faster you clear the screen like this the more points you get. This is a really fast and fun game and the music is perfectly paced to get your thumbs moving like lightning.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>magdrop3</set>
	<manufacturer>Data East</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1997</year>
	<size>174</size>
	<desc>Magical Drop 3 follows the same puzzle style as the first game but also selectable characters and a range of game modes. The pace of the game is also even faster meaning you probably have crippled thumbs after playing for a while. Its great fast paced fun though.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>maglord</set>
	<manufacturer>Alpha Denshi</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Platform Adventure</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc>This game reminds me a lot of Shadow of the Beast on the Amiga, you play as a magician battling across the land to save the world from an evil overlord and his minions, you can change into different forms as you progress through the game including a dragon and a ninja, and utilise their powers, Its quite a neat action platform game but nothing revolutionary.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>mahretsu</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Mahjong</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>42</size>
	<desc>Im afraid I dont know how to play mahjong or read japanese, so I cant really rate this game.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>marukodq</set>
	<manufacturer>Takara</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Quiz</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>118</size>
	<desc>A game based around a quiz show, However, all the questions are in japanese, so unfortunately I cant read them or play the game properly.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>miexchng</set>
	<manufacturer>Face</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1997</year>
	<size>78</size>
	<desc>This game plays almost identically to the Magical Drop games, the main difference being that the theme of this game is money you have to grab coins of a certain value and place them next to one another making them disappear and clear the screen.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>minasan</set>
	<manufacturer>Monolith</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Mahjong</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>54</size>
	<desc>I`m afraid I don`t know how to play mahjong, so I can`t really rate this game, its also in Japanese which doesn`t help. That may be a good thing though, saying its bizarre doesnt do justice to the wierdness of this game *shudder*.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>mosyougi</set>
	<manufacturer>ADK</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>58</size>
	<desc>This is another japanese puzzle game, unfortunately I cannot read the text so I cant comment on the game.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>mslug</set>
	<manufacturer>Nazca</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Platform Shooter</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>193</size>
	<desc>Another true classic neogeo game, a platform shooter like this could only be done this well on the neo. There are brilliant level designs, weapons and action all the way through the game, the end of level bosses are particularly impressive. A top notch Arcade shooter.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>mslug2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Platform Shooter</genre>
	<year>1998</year>
	<size>362</size>
	<desc>Metal Slug 2 builds on the brilliance of the first game with even more great features including selectable characters and new weapons and enemies plus even more spectacular bosses.</desc>
	<rating>17</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>mslugx</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Platform Shooter</genre>
	<year>1999</year>
	<size>506</size>
	<desc>Metal Slug X is not a true sequel to Metal Slug 2 but more of an Update. Much of the game is the same as its predecessor however some of the levels have been modified, (e.g the first desert level is now set at night) I have heard that there are also extra secret levels and new weapons, It is not significantly better than MS2 but is just as good.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>mslug3</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Platform Shooter</genre>
	<year>2000</year>
	<size>708</size>
	<desc>I havent had the opportunity to play this yet but if its as good as its predecessors its a winner.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>mslug4</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK/Playmore</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Platform Shooter</genre>
	<year>2002</year>
	<size>576</size>
	<desc>I havent had the opportunity to play this yet but if its as good as its predecessors its a winner.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>mutnat</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Fighter</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>54</size>
	<desc>Mutation nation is a scrolling beat em up, pitting you against hordes of mutated creatures, the game features a powerup system whereby you collect items dropped by enemies which provide you with special powers such as fireballs, dash attacks etc. Its not the best scrolling fighter on the neo but its a good playable game.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>nam1975</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Third Person Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc>This is the neogeo equivalent of the arcade shooter Cabal you control your soldier in the forerground and aim your weapon using the crosshair, so you must keep a careful balance between shooting and avoiding enemy bullets.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>ncombat</set>
	<manufacturer>Alpha Denshi</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Fighter</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc>Ninja Combat is an early neogeo scrolling beat em up, It has the usual range of enemies and weapons which you see in these types of games and it plays ok in the short term, however it does look quite dated these days and the graphics are not exactly the best you can find on the Neo.</desc>
	<rating>10</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>ncommand</set>
	<manufacturer>Alpha Denshi</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Vertical Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>54</size>
	<desc>Just as Nam1975 is effectively the neogeo version of Cabal, this game is the equivalent of Mercs, Its a two player vertical scrolling shooter with power-ups galore and a range of ninja weapons.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>neobombe</set>
	<manufacturer>Hudson</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1997</year>
	<size>138</size>
	<desc>The classic BomberMan in neogeo form, negotiate the maze and plant bombs to destroy your enemies whilst trying not to blow yourself up. Just as good here as in its other incarnations.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>neocup98</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Football/Soccer</genre>
	<year>1998</year>
	<size>162</size>
	<desc>For some reason SNK decided to take a step back for NeoGeo Cup 98, this game uses the SSK3 game engine rather than SSK4, maybe neo players decided that they preferred the v3 engine and SNK listened? whatever the reason, it was another new sequel for another new year, though to be honest little has changed.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>neodrift</set>
	<manufacturer>Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Rally Driving</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>106</size>
	<desc>There arent many driving games on the neogeo and this is probably one of the best. You drive your rallycar around the winding track whilst trying not to smash into the walls. It has an unusual pseudo 3D viewpoint which Ive only seen in one other game Overtop (which is also a neogeo game). but you need quick reflexes to get around the track without crashing.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>neomrdo</set>
	<manufacturer>Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>50</size>
	<desc>The neogeo enhanced version of the well known Mr Do!. The game is basically a combination of pac man and diggerman. You must collect the items in the level by digging through the objects in your way and avoid the wandering enemies.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>neonopon</set>
	<manufacturer>Blastar</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>2002</year>
	<size>?</size>
	<desc>This appears to be a Homebrew game which is only playable in emulators. It`s another Puzzle Tetris/Magical Drop style game, and although basic, is quite impressive for a home made game.</desc>
	<rating>12</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>neopong</set>
	<manufacturer>NeoDev</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>2002</year>
	<size>?</size>
	<desc>I understand this is a homebrew game which is only playable in emulators. and its Pong! nuff said.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>ninjamast</set>
	<manufacturer>ADK/SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>330</size>
	<desc>For some reason I really like this game, the graphics arent the best youll find on neogeo but the game has a great atmosphere to it, it feels like its really authentic ancient japanese, plus the characters have some great moves and some really satisfying combos.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>nitd</set>
	<manufacturer>Gavaking / Eleven</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Platform</genre>
	<year>2000</year>
	<size>166</size>
	<desc>Another newer game I havent had the opportunity to play, looks kind of similar to Mario Bros.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>overtop</set>
	<manufacturer>ADK</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Driving</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>212</size>
	<desc>Overtop looks and plays very much like Neo Driftout, except that this game is based on street racing rather than rallying. As with Driftout the game is very playable if a bit tricky, you need quick reflexes to anticipate the corners. The graphics and animation are also pretty good.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>panicbom</set>
	<manufacturer>Hudson</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc>A combination of the hit bomberman games and the tetris theme. you match up bombers of the same colour to clear the screen, bombs also drop down to spice up the action.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>pbobblen</set>
	<manufacturer>Taito</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>32</size>
	<desc> A classic neogeo game, which has spawned dozens of sequels on a variety of computer systems.
A really simple but fun to play game, shoot coloured baloons from the bottom of the screen to the corresponding colour at the top to pop them and clear the screen.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>pbobbl2n</set>
	<manufacturer>Taito</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1999</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc> A classic neogeo game, which has spawned dozens of sequels on a variety of computer systems.
A really simple but fun to play game, shoot coloured baloons from the bottom of the screen to the corresponding colour at the top to pop them and clear the screen. </desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>pgoal</set>
	<manufacturer>Saurus</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Football/Soccer</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>146</size>
	<desc>A quick and simple 5-a-side football game, the smaller pitch and fewer players means there is lots of action rather than just chasing after the ball.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>popbounc</set>
	<manufacturer>Video System</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1997</year>
	<size>58</size>
	<desc> Again, another puzzle game, this time appearing as a combination of `puzzle bobble` `pong` and `breakout`.
It is quite playable, although I tend to find these bouncing ball style games quite annoying after a while as they can get really tricky when your bat just wont move fast enough.</desc>
	<rating>12</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>preisle2</set>
	<manufacturer>Yumekobo</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Horizontally Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1999</year>
	<size>478</size>
	<desc>Havent played this one, but its made by the manufacturers of Blazing Star so its likely to to be a quality shooter.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>pspikes2</set>
	<manufacturer>Video System</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Volleyball</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>82</size>
	<desc>Power Spikes 2 is a futuristic volleyball game, Im not sure if this game works correctly with emulators, as the computer teams AI seems to be almost non exsistent, the players dont even try to hit the ball. however I have played the game in the arcade and it seems fairly entertaining, however its not particularly outstanding.</desc>
	<rating>11</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>pulstar</set>
	<manufacturer>Aicom</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Horizontally Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>305</size>
	<desc>Pulstar is the Prequel to the excellent Blazing Star, this was one of the first neogeo games to use 3D rendered graphics in its intro sequence, which for its time are quite impressive. This is a good quality action shooter, however it does suffer from the dreaded restart points so you end up re-playing difficult parts of levels over and over which can become somewhat annoying. Thankfully Blazing Star overcame this problem by letting you continue from where you left off.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>puzzledp</set>
	<manufacturer>Taito/Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>30</size>
	<desc>This game is virtually identical to Puzzle Bobble and plays in the same way; match up the coloured baloons to clear the stage. Its not really any better than Puzzle Bobble but is just as playable.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>puzzldpr</set>
	<manufacturer>Taito/Visco</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Puzzle/Skill</genre>
	<year>1997</year>
	<size>32</size>
	<desc>An update to the original Puzzle De Pon, although Im not entirely sure what the differences are apart from some new colour schemes. Seems to play just like the original, just more levels maybe?</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>quizdais</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Quiz</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>34</size>
	<desc>This is a quiz game based around a story, as you progress through the game you meet different characters who ask you questions which you must answer correctly to progress. However, all the questions are in japanese, so unfortunately I cant read them or play the game properly.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>quizdai2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Quiz</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>50</size>
	<desc>The sequel to the first Quiz Daisousasen, the game still follows a story and you progress by answering questions. However, all the questions are in japanese, so unfortunately I cant read them or play the game properly.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>quizkof</set>
	<manufacturer>Saurus</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Quiz</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>122</size>
	<desc>Yet another quiz game this time based on the King of Fighters series. However, all the questions are in japanese, so unfortunately I cant read them or play the game properly.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>rageotd</set>
	<manufacturer>Evoga</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>2002</year>
	<size>?</size>
	<desc> This one was a bit of a surprize, it appears to be a sequel to Double Dragon, and looks excellent. The animation and artwork are top-notch and the game features a wide range of characters (including Billy and Jimmy) who have a superb anime styling to them, plus you can have tag matches as in Kizuna Encounter.
Now if I could just find it somewhere so I can play it ...</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>ragnagrd</set>
	<manufacturer>Saurus</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>338</size>
	<desc>A quite unusual beat-em up for the neogeo, this game uses 3D rendered graphics throughout as opposed to the usual 2D hand drawn style. The game itself plays ok, but It doesent have quite the same feel to it as some of the other neogeo fighters. And as CG development have moved on so much over recent years the graphics look rather dated in places and the animation, although smooth is not particularly realistic.</desc>
	<rating>12</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>rbff1</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>346</size>
	<desc>The first in the new-generation of the fatal fury games. With the Real Bout series SNK brought fatal fury up to date with the quality of the King of fighters games. This game still retains many of the original Fatal furys destinctive features such as sidestepping into the fore and background and many of the games popular characters such as Terry, Andy and Mai. But it also adds a much better combo system, power moves and SNKs stylised trademark graphics. A big improvement on the old FF games.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>rbffspec</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>394</size>
	<desc>A half-sequel between RBFF1 and 2, this game adds a range of new moves and locations and the return of some old characters such as Duck king and Tung fu rue. Not quite as classy as RBFF2 but a worthwile improvment on RBFF1.</desc>
	<rating>17</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>rbffspec</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1998</year>
	<size>539</size>
	<desc>The sequel to RBFF1, the main enhancements include further improved graphics, especially the intro and player select screens, plus there are some excellent new backgrounds and two new characters. If you liked the first game youll love this.</desc>
	<rating>17</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>ridhero</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Motorbike Racing</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc>I think this is the only motorbiking game for the neogeo, I remember playing this in the arcade, it is a fairly good racer, not really revolutionary or significantly better than any other motorbike game from the time but its good fun.</desc>
	<rating>12</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>roboarmy</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Fighter</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>45</size>
	<desc>Another fairly early neogeo scrolling fighter, however this game does have more class to it than some of its counterparts, for once you actually feel like youre hitting something as you battle through the game, there are also numerous powerups and vehicles to utilise as you battle against the seeminly endless robot army. Not brilliant, but one of the better of its kind on the neo.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>s1945p</set>
	<manufacturer>Psikyo</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Vertical Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1999</year>
	<size>681</size>
	<desc>Another newer game I havent played yet. Seems similar to Ghost Pilots but with all round improvements.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>samsho</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1993</year>
	<size>118</size>
	<desc> The first of the epic samurai shodown series (also known as samurai spirits). This game has great atmosphere and some quite original features for its time, such as Galford the ninja whos dog fights alongside him and can be used during special attacks. Good stuff.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>samsho2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>202</size>
	<desc>Samurai Shodown 2 builds on the success of the first game with new characters and stages, plus a range of new attacks. It is not massively better than the original but an improvement nonetheless.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>samsho3</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>282</size>
	<desc>SS 3 has a slightly different look to it than the previous games, it seems somewhat smoother and perhaps more refined. Again we see new characters, moves and backgrounds amongst other improvements, It plays very well, but I cant help but feel that something has been lost from the original, perhaps evolving the game into a new form.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>samsho4</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>378</size>
	<desc>The final neogeo Samurai Shodown game, when you play this game you can clearly see the path of evolution the series has taken over the years, this game takes all the best elements from its predecessors and merges them seamlessly, with an excellent range of characters and top notch anime style graphics this is a classy game all round.</desc>
	<rating>17</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>savagere</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>190</size>
	<desc> This was the game which spawned the excellent Kizuna Encounter, whilst not as impressive as its sequel, it does posess some original features of its own. Most notably the game features Multi-Level fighting, meaning characters can jump between various floor levels within a stage, i.e on the docks level characters can leap from the floor to the pipes above whilst still attacking with projectile weapons.
In some ways the game kind of feels like a mish-mash of ideas trying to be original. There are some bizarre characters such as the clown who attacks with a jack-in-the-box, the dancer who uses a bouncing ball and the main character Hayate, a martial arts master who uses a boomerang, wierd.
Nonetheless the game still plays well and is definitely worthy of attention.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>sdodgeb</set>
	<manufacturer>Technos</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>190</size>
	<desc>One of the more unusual neogeo games, you control a team of three players, trying to knock down the other team in a spectacular game of dodgeball. Throw with too little power and your opponent will catch the ball and hit you back, but hit with a special attack and the other team will be reeling. Original and good fun.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>sengoku</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Fighter</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>55</size>
	<desc>A scrolling fighter, you play as the hero defending earth against an anicent samurai overlord who has returned to wreak havoc on the world. This plays almost identically to mutation nation, you pick up power-pills along the way with give you special abilities as you slash you way to victory. This game would be quite gory if the blood werent blue. Overall ok, but not great.</desc>
	<rating>11</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>sengoku2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Fighter</genre>
	<year>1993</year>
	<size>74</size>
	<desc>A big improvement on the first Sengoku, this games main new feature is in the ability to earn new characters along the way, allowing you to build up a tag-team of sorts. When you get the appropriate powerups, you can tag with a range of other characters including a samurai, a cowboy, a ninja and even an armoured wolf.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>sengoku3</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK/Noise Factory</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Fighter</genre>
	<year>2001</year>
	<size>364</size>
	<desc>It took a long time but finally the NeoGeo has a scrolling fighter equally as good as those made by capcom. Sengoku 3 takes the best elements from its predecessors and combines them with superb graphics varied characters and top combo action.</desc>
	<rating>17</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>shocktro</set>
	<manufacturer>Saurus</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Vertical Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1997</year>
	<size>346</size>
	<desc>Much like Metal Slug, you play as one of a group of soldiers battling against and overwhelming force in this arcade scrolling shooter, however rather than being a horizontal platform based shooter like MS, Shock Troopers scrolls vertically much like capcoms mercs. Another real piece of neogeo class.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>shocktr2</set>
	<manufacturer>Saurus</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Vertical Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1998</year>
	<size>514</size>
	<desc>Building on the original, Second Squad gives you more characters, more weapons more enemies and better graphics, what more could you ask for? Excellent shooter action.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>socbrawl</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Football/Soccer</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc>SoccerBrawl, comes from that great era of fururistic sports games in the early 90s, Its by no means the best football game on the neo but it is fun over the top arcade action, when your power meter is maxed you can pull off some spectacular moves, filling the screen with energy bursts, even the goalkeeper leaves trails of smoke from his feet as he is forced backward by the power of the ball.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>sonicwi2</set>
	<manufacturer>Video System</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Vertical Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>102</size>
	<desc>This is one of those spectacular arcade scrolling shooters, you choose from a range of fighter planes and power up you weapons along the way. Two player action with maximum weapons is a real destruction fest, virtually nothing can survive your onslaught, though the bosses are quite resilient.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>sonicwi3</set>
	<manufacturer>Video System</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Vertical Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>154</size>
	<desc> This sequel builds on its predecessor in the usual style, more planes, more waepons, more enemies, more action.
If you liked Sonic Wings 2 game youll love this.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>spinmast</set>
	<manufacturer>Data East</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Platform</genre>
	<year>1993</year>
	<size>90</size>
	<desc>An oddball platform game, in some ways its similar to metal slug, but is more limited. The main feature of the game is that you attack with your yoyo, im not sure if this was supposed to be one of those non-violent games, but it doesent strike me as the most effective weapon to use against a legion of enemies!? It plays in the usual platform style and is quite playable, good but not great.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>ssideki</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Football/Soccer</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>54</size>
	<desc>I remember playing this game while at college, every lunchtime we would go to the arcade and spend way to much money on the machine. If youre looking for no-messing all action football, look no further, this game is superb.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>ssideki2</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Football/Soccer</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>106</size>
	<desc>SSK2 changed the format of the game somewhat, everything now has a much more realistic look to it rather than the animated style of the original. I suppose that technically this is an improvement. but I feel that it lost the atmosphere of the original.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>ssideki3</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Football/Soccer</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>158</size>
	<desc>More improvements to the style set by SSK2. SSK3 gives more options and teams and further improved graphics, thers also a new powerup mode which give your players special abilites, adding a little more variety.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>ssideki4</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Football/Soccer</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>226</size>
	<desc>More of the same as the series continues SNK have added some extra options again and the game again has a slightly different look with a different perspective and larger sprites. Again, technically its an improvement but it doesent really make a significant difference.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>stakwin</set>
	<manufacturer>Saurus</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Horse Racing</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>98</size>
	<desc>Now this is a sport you dont see depicted very often in games- horseracing, yep the neo is THE system for unusual games. This game works surprisingly well, and is in many ways just as good as other racing games.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>stakwin2</set>
	<manufacturer>Saurus</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Horse Racing</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>178</size>
	<desc>More horseracing, much the same as the first game but with extra options and better graphics.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>strhoop</set>
	<manufacturer>Data East</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Basketball</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>94</size>
	<desc>I think this is the only basketball game on the neo so it has little competition, however this game can hold its own anyway, it plays much like the NBA arcade games but in a street setting.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>superspy</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>First Person Combat</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>55</size>
	<desc>You could think of this game as a 2D first person shooter, it plays kind of like doom on PC, but you can only move left or right, forward or back, (remember, neogeo wasnt designed to do 3D graphics) nonetheless this is a pretty original game, there is a range of weapons including knives, machineguns, and your bare fists. A quality game.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>tophuntr</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Platform</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>110</size>
	<desc>Another side-scrolling platformer, similar to metal slug. You can defeat enemies with your fists or objects you find along the way. Graphics are much better than some of the more average platformers, some backgrounds are particularly detailed. One of the better platformers on the neo.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>tpgolf</set>
	<manufacturer>SNK</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Golf</genre>
	<year>1990</year>
	<size>62</size>
	<desc>This early neogeo game was quite revolutionary for its time, the neo allowed far superior graphics than had been seen in in previous golf games, here you get huge sprites, multiple viewpoints and zooooming action. By todays standards it looks a little dated but as golf games go, its still pretty good.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>trally</set>
	<manufacturer>ADK</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Rallying</genre>
	<year>1991</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc>One of the few driving games on the neo, this one plays much like micro machines (i wonder which was though up first?) It doesent look quite as impressive as Neo Driftout or Overtop put still plays well enough, although you will crash a lot until you learn the tracks well.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>turfmast</set>
	<manufacturer>Nazca</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Golf</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>133</size>
	<desc> The only other golf game on the neo besides Top Players Golf. This one is a few years newer, with far more realistic graphics and animation, it comes from the makers of Metal Slug, so you know the graphics are going to be top notch.
It also plays pretty well too, It combines the quality of a simulation game with the fun of an arcade game.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>twinspri</set>
	<manufacturer>ADK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Scrolling Shooter / Puzzle</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>146</size>
	<desc> This is quite an original game, it combines two of the neo`s most popular genre`s: puzzlers and shooters.
The screen is split in half meaning that you battle against either a second player or the computer as well as against the game`s wealth of enemies. There`s loads of action and the later levels can get really frantic.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>tws96</set>
	<manufacturer>ADK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Football/Soccer</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>122</size>
	<desc>TWS`96 plays much the same as many of the other neo football games, (after all there`s only so much you can do with one type of game). The graphics have a slightly different styling to them than the SSK series, but at the end of the day football is football and it plays much the same.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>viewpoin</set>
	<manufacturer>Sammy</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Isometric Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>74</size>
	<desc>One of the neo`s more unusual shooters, it uses 3D rendered graphics to create a kind of pseudo 3D, isometric blaster. The unusual perspective makes it tricky to get used to but once you get into it youll find you`ve got a quality game on your hands.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>vliner</set>
	<manufacturer>Dyna</manufacturer>
	<players>1</players>
	<genre>Fruit Machine Sim</genre>
	<year>2001</year>
	<size>?</size>
	<desc>I havent played this one yet, but it looks pretty accurate, so if you like fruit machines you`ll probably like this.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>wakuwak7</set>
	<manufacturer>Sunsoft</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1996</year>
	<size>259</size>
	<desc>This one-on-one fighter has some great styling, everything is drawn in a distinct anime style and the attention to detail is fantastic. As the name points out there are only 7 characters to choose from, but their bizarre nature, ranging from the typical martial arts enthusiast to a pair of little guys who drive a battletank, more than makes up for it.</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>wh1</set>
	<manufacturer>ADK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1992</year>
	<size>82</size>
	<desc>World Heroes started out as just another Street Fighter 2 clone, many of the characters are remarkably similar to their streetfighter counterparts, particularly the ninjas Hanzo and Fuuma (Ryu and Ken anyone?). The game does however sport some backgrounds which are arguably more impressive than those of SF2, particularly the bell-tower stage which has series of huge rotating cogs. WH is not as `deep` a game as many other fighters but it is good fun especially if you`re a big fan of 2D fighters.</desc>
	<rating>13</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>wh2</set>
	<manufacturer>ADK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1993</year>
	<size>146</size>
	<desc>ADK learned from the criticisms of WH1 and made some good improvements with the sequel, This game adds some new and improved characters such as Captain Kidd and an evil-looking American Footballer. the game also has a faster pace meaning you can pull off some pretty damaging combos.</desc>
	<rating>15</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>wh2j</set>
	<manufacturer>ADK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>178</size>
	<desc>WH2 Jet was intended as an update to WH2, much like SF2 Turbo, the main new feature is the tournament mode which offers cinematic sequences between battles, plus there are some more new characters and moves and an extra speed boost (hence the name).</desc>
	<rating>16</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>whp</set>
	<manufacturer>ADK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>1on1 Fighter</genre>
	<year>1995</year>
	<size>226</size>
	<desc>The final World Heroes game, I`m not sure if this was intended as another update or a true sequel, The main new feature is the `Hero` bar (seen at the bottom of the screen) which is much the same as many other beat em ups, letting you do super powerful moves when the bar fills, new backgrounds and gameplay tweaks are also the order of the day, and whilst the game is not significantly different than it`s predecessors, it is the best of the series.</desc>
	<rating>17</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>wjammers</set>
	<manufacturer>Data East</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Airhockey</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>74</size>
	<desc>This game plays kind of like the air-hockey tables you find in amusement arcades, and is even more tricky. I found it quite irritating at first as the computer seems to be too good, but once you get the hang of it you`ll be able to counter the computers moves pretty well. Personally I prefer `Battle Flipshot` to this, even though the two are quite similar, BF seems more polished and playable.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>zedblade</set>
	<manufacturer>NMK</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Horizontal Scrolling Shooter</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>110</size>
	<desc>Zed Blade reminds me of the arcade shooter `Silkworm`, it has a similar look and feel to it. There are the usual enemies, powerups and stages to play through and find, plus the graphics arent bad either. This game is by no means the best shooter on the neo, but it is worth playing.</desc>
	<rating>14</rating>
</info>
<info>
	<set>zupapa</set>
	<manufacturer>Face</manufacturer>
	<players>1 or 2</players>
	<genre>Platform</genre>
	<year>1994</year>
	<size>46</size>
	<desc>One I havent played yet, It looks similar to the Mario Bros/Bubble Bobble kind of games.</desc>
	<rating>?</rating>
</info>
</roms>
